

RAHUL MOTIYAR

Portfolio Phone

E-Mail

rahulmotiyar.me +31 685145769

rahulmotiyar@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Master's in Interaction Design IIT Bombay, India - 2013

Bachelor's in Technology Electronics, RTU, India - 2010

DESIGN AWARDS

IF Design Award 2020 Red Dot Design Award 2018 IF Design Award 2017

UX SKILLS

SAFe, PDLM & AD Co-Create Facilitation Interaction Design Service blueprinting Visual Design User Research Rapid Prototyping

UI BUILDING

Sketch Framer Adobe suite

3D MODELLING

AutoCAD Rhino Keyshot

MOVIE EDITORS

After effects Final Cut Pro

PROGRAMMING

Arduino Processing HTML/CSS

LANGUAGE

English, Hindi, Rajasthani

NATIONALITY

Indian
Residence permit holder
In the Netherlands

DATE OF BIRTH

10 March 1988

ADDRESS

Jan Heurkensstrat 1, 5667 BL, Geldrop The Netherlands

PROFILE

I am an interaction designer with 10 years of experience in various domains like Healthcare, Serviceability, Informatics. I help organisation to strategically build meaningful products for their customers and users. I am well versed with design tools, UX skills for facilitating Co-creation workshops with customers & cross functional teams. I possess excellent physical & digital prototyping skills. I am currently Design Lead on Camera based innovation projects at Philips Design based out of Netherlands.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGN LEAD & RESEARCHER, PHILIPS DESIGN, NETHERLANDS NOV 2021 - CURRENT

- Leading Camera Based Innovations in CT & DXR in Advanced development program that helps in automate workflows, motion detection & image correction, provide real-time positioning guidance to patients & radiographers, reduce repeat scans caused due to poor positioning or motion artifacts.
- Facilitate Co-Create with clinical science, Customers & Research scientists.
- Generate workflows and research methodology for concept validation.
- ICBE Submission, approvals, Formative & Summative tests in physical setup
- IP Generation and drive it to submission with IP Council.

SR. USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN, PHILIPS DESIGN, INDIA

APR 2015 - OCT 2021

- Led a team of 5 UX & 2 Usability engineers to deliver Harmonized workflow and image acquisition experience to radiographers and operators in operating MRI, CT & DXR consoles.
- Facilitated various Co-Create workshops with clinical science, (MR, CT & DXR) business units to gather user needs & system requirements of different imaging devices.
- Build various low fidelity wireframes in an iterative process, build interactive mockups to run clinical scenarios with users & customers.
- Delivered mid-fidelity approved final concepts to Design Delivery team to build visual designs.

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER, PHILIPS DESIGN, INDIA

OCT 2013 - MAR 2015

- Studied role of Field service, Remote service & remote monitoring engineers and helped Philips serviceability team in improving Remote ticketing & Servicing tool. The UX of the tool vastly improved in reducing the resolution time to 20% and the products guarantees 99% uptime for healthcare devices installed across the globe by Philips. The product (IDM) received IF Design award in 2020.
- Responsible in improving various Healthcare informatics & Primary care & Monitoring products, Improved UX/UI for research-based products like Genomics informatics & Remote consultative critical care products.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE JAN 2012 – APR 2012

- Conducted primary user-research in India and build solutions around eye free & touch free interfaces.
- Came up with idea of Smart Medicine for chronic patients which reminds patients when it's time to take medicine.
- Build prototype and tested with 3 users & applied for IP submission with IIT-Bombay & NUS